Michael Artes

Location: Baltimore, Maryland 21207
Phone: 410-236-6213 | Email: Artes.mike@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-artes-1380a819a/
Github: https://github.com/michaelartes89

Portfolio: https://react-protfolio-ma89.herokuapp.com/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer & Project Manager with career experience that ranges from grassroots non-profit organizations to large industry leading corporations. Always engaged, innovative, and up-beat. Often described as the kind of person that is a pleasure to come to work with each day.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js

PROJECTS

Off-The-Menu

Gitlab: https://gitlab.com/off-the-menu

Deployed Page: https://otm-online.firebaseapp.com/Login

- Motivated by the experience of approx. 30 million Americans with food allergies, this prototype web app allows users to search local restaurant menus and find items which are safe to them to eat
- Personal responsibly: original app idea, project management, created React components for homepage, API routes for user data, database content management
- Technologies used: ReactJS, MongoDB, Tailwind CSS, Firebase

Professional Experience

Sabbatical

Artes Family Baltimore, MD

August 2018-Present

- Took time away from work to care for a family member
- Began professional development though Johns Hopkins Web Development Bootcamp in September 2019

U.S. Bank

Personal Banker & Inbound Sales Banker Portland, OR/Denver, CO

Jan 2016-August 2018

- Preformed sales and service transactions via phone from an inbound call center
- Created outstanding customer experiences and developed high quality bank relationships
- Earned promotion to financial sales position in Q3 2016 by demonstrating 3+ months of scorecard balance
- Recognized in 2017 year-end evaluation for over 100% performance YTD in all weighted metrics
- Transferred back to service dept in 2018 to further develop leadership skills- acted as a peer-to-peer coaching leader and contributed to management strategies
- Propelled team to number 1 position in department stack rank during every month of my tenure in 2018

Verizon Wireless

Corporate Retail Sales Representative, Denver, CO

Aug 2013- July 2015

- Preformed sales and customer service transactions in a busy retail store environment
- Earned "Rookie of the Year" award with highest overall composite score for all tracked performance metrics among new hires in 2013
- Finalist in 2014 "Rockstar" contest (Verizon's competitive sales demonstration contest)

Additional Experience:

Clean Water Action-Field Manager & Online Communications Intern (2011-2013)

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: Johns Hopkins University Baltimore, MD

April 2020

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap,Node JS, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor of Arts: University of Maryland College Park, MD

Major: Government and Politics GPA 3.2

May 2011